Guide to the John McComb Architectural Drawings Finding Aid 1766-1829 PR 40
New-York Historical Society
- Dominic Lynch House ink, LL-LR: "Principal floor of Dom.k Lynch's House - at West Chester", 92862 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 236)
- Dominic Lynch House, 92861 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 238)
- Dominic Lynch House ink, LC-LR: "Basement floor of Dominic Lynches House at West Chester", 92860 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 237)
- Door sketch, attrib. Arched doorway with keystone: attrib., 92859 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 424 verso)
- Doors Door frames - 4 designs: attributed, 1799; 92858 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 379)
- Doors Door openings with Gibbsian reveals: attributed, 92857 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 380)
- Doorway designs (3), attrib., 92856 (Box McComb Box 17, Item 336)
- Doorways - 2, attrib., 92855 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 310)
- Duane Street Church ink, LC: "duane street", 92854 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 263)
- E. Leavenworths and Wm. Coits House ink, LL-LC: "Plan of W.m Coits House, Brooklyn", 92853 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 269b 1/2 verso)
- Ear Trumpet, attributed, 92852 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 205b verso)
- Educational institution, 92851 (Box McComb box 6, Item 112)
- Educational institution verso, ink, UC-UR: "The written plan approved & adopted by the Board of Trustees March 3d 1808 Wm. P. Deare Att.", 1808, ink verso UC-UR; 92850 (Box McComb box 6, Item 111)
- Educational institution, 92849 (Box McComb box 6, Item 113)
- Eldridge St. No. 48, Map verso, ink, UC: "Map of Ground in Eldridge St No 48", 1825, April 15; 92848 (Box McComb Box 17, Item 346)
- Elevation, unidentified, 92847 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 85)
- Elevation, unidentified, 92846 (Box McComb Box 17, Item 339 (1))
- Elevation, unidentified, 92845 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 246)
- Engraving "FLORE": LC, 92844 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 4)
- Engraving "In the Collection of Dr. Mead": LL-LC, 92843 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 005b)
- Engraving "LE POEME PASTORAL.": LL-LR, 92842 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 004b)
- Engraving "Bacchus.": LC, 92841 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 004a)
- Engraving "Monument of Hevelius at Dantzick.": LL-LR, 92840 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 3)
- Engraving "A CAR. DE FARNESIO SRE VICEC.": UL-UR, 92839 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 6)
- Engraving Female Figure as Church of England: attrib., 92838 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 4)
- Engraving Crowning of Seated Man with Putti: attrib., 92837 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 458)
- Engraving "L'HYVER": LC, 92836 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 004c)
- Engraving Tools to Move Stone: attrib., 92835 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 479)
- Engraving "Avanzi del Tempio del Dio Canopo nella Villa Adriana in Tivoli": LC, 92834 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 467)
- Engraving "Veduta dell' Arco di Tito": LC, 92833 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 483)
- Engraving "Veduta della fonte e delle Spelonche d' Egeria fuor della porta Capena or di S. Seb.no": LR, 92832 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 489)
- Engraving Architectural Details: attrib., 92831 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 477)
- Engraving "Tempio antico volgarmente detto della Salute": LC-LR, 92830 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 488)
- Engraving "Veduta dell' interno dell' Amfiteatro Flavio detto il Colosseo": LL-LC, 92829 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 487)
- Engraving Antique Marble Vase and Pedestal: attrib., 92828 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 480)
- Engraving "Vue de la Place de Banchi": LL, 92827 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 465)
- Engraving "Veduta di una parte de' fondamenti del Teatro di Marcello": LL-LR, 92826 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 471)
- Engraving "PROSPECTVS MONTIS VENTORVM, QVI DICITVR CAROLINVS PROPE VRBEM CASSEL AQVARVM DECIDENTIVM LVSIBVS, FONTIVM, ARBORVM, AC STATVARVM DISPOSITIONE, 92825 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 462)
- Engraving 2 Antique Vases: attrib., 92824 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 482)
- Engraving "Frammenti della Camera sepolcrale dirimpetto alla Chiesa di S. Sebast.o fuori delle mura": LL-LR, 92823 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 476)
- Engraving Architectural Details from various Villas and Palazzos: attrib., 92822 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 478)
- Engraving Interior View of the Temple of Neptune: attrib., 92821 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 466)
- Engraving "DIVO - ANTONINO - AVG - PIO ANTONINVS - AVGVSTVS - ET VERVS - AVGVSTVS - FILII": UC, 92820 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 481)
- Engraving "Vue de la Englise de Carignano": LL, 92819 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 464)
- Engraving "Veduta del Tempio ottangolare di Minerva Medica": LL-LC, 92818 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 468)
- Engraving "Avanzi del Tempio detto di Apollo nella Villa Adriana vicini a Tivoli": LR, 92817 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 492)
- Engraving "Avanzi della Villa di Mecenate a Tivoli, costruita di travertini a opera incerta": LL, 92816 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 490)
- Engraving "Al Signore Egidio Earle Cavaliere Inglese amtore delle belle arti": UL-UR, 92815 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 469)
- Engraving "Veduta sul Monte Quirinale del Palazzo dell' Eccellentissima Casa Barberini, Architettura del Cav.r Bernino": LL-LR, 92814 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 493)
- Engraving "Veduta del Tempio, detto della Tosse": LC-LR, 92813 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 486)
- Engraving "Sepolcro di Cecilia Metella": LL-LC, 92812 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 484)
- Engraving "VEDUTA in-terna della Chiesa della Madonna degli Angioli detta della Certosa, che anticam.e era la principal Sala delle Terme di Diocleziano., 92811 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 495)
- Engraving "Modo col quale furono alzati grossi Travertini, e gli altri Marmi nel fabbricare il gran Sepolcro di Cecilia Metella, oggi detto capo di Bove, 92810 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 475)
- Engraving "Veduta in prospettiva dell' altro Candelabro antico che si vede nel Museo del Cavalier Piranesi": UL-UR, 92809 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 472)
- Engraving "Veduta della Villa dell' Emo Sig.r Card Alesandro Albani fuori di Porta Salaria": LR, 92808 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 496)
- Engraving "Altra Veduta del tempio della Sibilla in Tivoli": LL, 92807 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 485)
- Engraving "Rovine delle Terme Antoniniane": LC, 92806 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 491)
- Engraving Antique Marble Vase: attrib., 92805 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 470)
- Engraving Stone details: attrib., 92804 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 474)
- Engraving "Vue du Palais de Monsieur Marcello Durazzo dans la rue Balbi": LL, 92803 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 463)
- Engraving "Veduta del Ponte Molle sul Tevere due miglia lontan da Roma": LC-LR, 92802 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 494)
- Engraving Trevi Fountain: attrib., 92801 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 473)
- Engraving "Avanzi di una Sala appar-tenente al Castro Pretorio nel-la Villa Adriana in Tivoli.": LC, 92800 (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 497)
- Engraving/Print "CHRIST CROWNED WITH THORNS": LL-LR, 92799 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 459)
- Engravings, 92798 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 2)
- Engravings "Kriegs Trophen.": LC, 92797 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 002b)
- Engravings Chinoiserie: attrib., 92796 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 002c)
- Engravings "Kriegs Trophen.": LC, 92795 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 002e)
- Engravings "No. 20.": LC, 92794 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 2)
- Engravings "Kriegs Trophen, Chez Fietta et Comp d' Kriegshaber pres d'Augsburg.": ink, LL-LR, 92793 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 002a)
- Engravings "Krigs Trophen.": ink, LC, 92792 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 2)
- Engravings "No. 20.": LC, 92791 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 002g)
- Engravings, 6 bound together Fireplace and Mantelpiece: attrib., 92790 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 001c)
- Engravings, 6 bound together Fireplace and Mantelpiece: attrib., 92789 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 001b)
- Engravings, 6 bound together Fireplace and Mantelpiece: attrib., 92788 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 001e)
- Engravings, 6 bound together Fireplace and Mantelpiece: attrib., 92787 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 001a)
- Engravings, 6 bound together "Nouveaux desseins de Cheminees a peu de Frais": MC-LC, 92786 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 1)
- Engravings, 6 bound together Fireplace and Mantelpiece (2 images): attrib., 92785 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 1)
- Entablature profile Profiles of entablatures: attributed, 92784 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 377 verso)
- Equestrian Amphitheatre ink, MC: "Horse Path", 92783 (Box McComb Box 21, Item 453)
- Erie Canal ink, LC: "Sectio thro' middle", 92782 (Box McComb Box 21, Item 455)
- Erie Canal ink, UL-UR: "ROADWAY CULVERT ON SECTION 318.", 92781 (Box McComb Box 21, Item 454)
- Etons Neck Lighthouse Ink, LC: "Plan, Elevation & Section of the different Buildings intended to be Erected at Etons Neck on Long Island New York", 1798, August 4 ink LC; 92780 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 82)
- Exterior Partial Elevation Sketch, attrib. One bay 1 3/4 stories with Gibbsian reveals: attrib., 92779 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 424)
- Female sketch, 92778 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 425 verso)
- Firehouse, 92777 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 265)
- Fireplaces Three fireplaces, six designs: attributed, 92776 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 377)
- Floor, manner of lowering Manner of lowering a floor without breaking it up. Ink ML to MR, 92775 (Box McComb box 2, Item 037a recto)
- Fort at Dunkirk [Chautauqua, NY] Pencil, LC: "Plan of a Fort at Dunkirk" Pile, Rack for Hoisting a gate, [1794]; 92774 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 81)
- Fort Diamond, 1817; 92773 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 160a recto)
- Fort Diamond ink, UC-UL: "drawings done for Fort diamond when the contract was made for the Stone-", 1817; 92772 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 160b verso)
- Fort William, attrib., 92771 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 161)
- Fort, unidentified, 92770 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 159b verso)
- Fort, unidentified, 92769 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 157)
- Fort, unidentified, 92768 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 156)
- Fort, unidentified, 92767 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 158a recto)
- Fort, unidentified, 92766 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 162)
- Fort, unidentified, 92765 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 159a recto)
- Fort, unidentified, 92764 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 163)
- Fort, unidentified, 92763 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 158b verso)
- Fort, unidentified, 92762 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 154)
- Fortification, plan for defense of slope [attrib.] ink, ML-MR: "Profile of the Body of the Place & the Revelin with Revetement", 92761 (Box McComb box 6, Item 102b verso)
- Fragment of a shield, axe, spear, points of picks and an oak leaf, attrib., 92760 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 308 verso)
- Framing of a roof and top of cupola, attrib., 92759 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 422)
- Framing of a roof, attrib., 92758 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 421)
- Framing of a roof, attributed ink, UR: "Top of Arch", 92757 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 420)
- Francis Childs House pencil, LL-LR: "Design'd for Mr Francis Childs", 92756 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 240)
- French's idea for a steam pump An Idea for a steam pump by W (Mr.?) French. Ink UC - UR, 92755 (Box McComb box 2, Item 36)
- Front stoop Front stoop, 92754 (Box McComb box 1, Item 022b)
- Furnace, 92753 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 90)
- G. Gilfert Seal, attrib., 92752 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 005a)
- Garden Folly, attributed, 92751 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 350)
- Gasner Property Plan Plan of Property belonging to the Heirs of Mr. John Gasner sold at auction Jany. Ink UL to UR, 92750 (Box McComb box 2, Item 037b verso)
- Gate, attrib., 92749 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 147)
- Geometric figures, 92748 (Box McComb box 2, Item 032a recto)
- Geometric figures, 92747 (Box McComb box 2, Item 032b verso)
- Gothic study, attrib. Gothic tracery with lozenge in center: attrib., 92746 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 304)
- Government House Main floor plan (attrib.), [1790]; 92745 (Box McComb box 3, Item 55)
- Government House North Elevation, Government House (attrib.), [1790]; 92744 (Box McComb box 3, Item 56)
- Government House Main floor plan (attrib.), [1790]; 92743 (Box McComb box 3, Item 57)
- Government House Main floor plan [attrib], 1790-1791; 92742 (Box McComb box 3, Item 058a recto)
- Government House, executed plan Main floor plan (attrib.), [1790]; 92741 (Box McComb box 3, Item 54)
- Government Mansion, attributed, 1790; 92740 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 395)
- Hoisting machine sketch, attrib. ink, UC-UR: "Hoisting machine taken from 13. Vol. of Repistory of the Arts Page 300", 92739 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 309)
- Hospital, unidentified, 92738 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 266a recto)
- House and store plan, attributed, 92737 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 411)
- House for a cotton manufactury House For a Cotton Manufactury, 92736 (Box McComb box 1, Item 025b verso)
- House, unidentified Dutch door with 2 panels below and 4 above: attributed, 1797; 92735 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 382)
- House, unidentified, 92734 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 411 verso)
- House, unidentified Front Elevation: attributed, 92733 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 409)
- House, unidentified, 92732 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 410)
- Houses - various plans, unidentified ink, LL-LC: "Two Plans for Single Houses of 45'- by 28'- 0"-", 92731 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 408)
- Hudson River to Lake Erie table of water levels Scale of Levels between Lake Erie and Hudson River. Ink, UL, 92730 (Box McComb box 2, Item 30)
- ink, UC-UR: "Supreme court door Rear Steps- The Roof" ink, UR: "The Recorders grate to be contra( )"..., 92729 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 353 verso)
- Insane asylum Plan of first floor for insane asylum: attributed, 92728 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 214)
- Kiln, [1794]; 92727 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 80)
- King, Rufus House Ink, LL-LR: "Two different Pitches of Roofs designed for Rufus King Esq. House", 92726 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 099a)
- King, Rufus House ink, LL-LR: "Elivation of a House design'd for Rufus King Esquire", 92725 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 241)
- King, Rufus House, elevation NA, 92724 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 099b)
- King, Rufus House, plans - pencil LR and pencil verso Plans of basement Story, Principal Floor, Bedchamber Floor [attrib.], 92723 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 98)
- Last Pan Last Pan, 92722 (Box McComb box 1, Item 022c)
- LeRoy, Bayards & Co stores ink, UL: "No S. First Class Hazards", 92721 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 255)
- Library, unidentified, 92720 (Box McComb box 4, Item 72)
- Lighthouse Ink, LC: "Top View of the Lamp when Complete", 92719 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 84)
- Lighthouse, 92718 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 83)
- Lighthouse at Cape Henry, 92717 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 75)
- Lighthouse at Cape Henry, 92716 (Drawer case 38 drawer 6, Item 77)
- Lighthouse at Eaton's Neck, L.I.N.Y., 92715 (Box McComb box 4, Item 78)
- London asylum, Guys Hospital. West Riding asylum Plan of the London Afsylum for the care & cure of the Insane by Jas. Bevans architect 1814. Ink LL. Lunatic House at Guys Hospital. Ink UR. On, 92714 (Box McComb box 2, Item 27)
- Lunatic asylum ink wash, LL-LR: "ELEVATIONS OF LUNATIC ASYLUM", 92713 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 268)
- Lunatic asylum "ASYLUM": MC, 1808; July 15; 92712 (Box McComb Box 22)
- Lunatic hospital ink, LL-LR: "Plan Showing how the Lunatic Hospital can be altered to make good accomodations for a Marine Hospital", 1826; 92711 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 213)
- Manhattan Water Works reservoir, [1799] wm. 1797; 92710 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 399)
- Map of Brooklyn waterfront & Governors Island, 92709 (Box McComb Box 21, Item 436)
- Map of lots along river block, attributed, 92708 (Box McComb Box 17, Item 347)
- Map of New York Harbor Ink, LR: "A Plan of the Harbour of New York from an Actual Survey made by Dirictions of the Corporation of a Millitary com. by Capt. J Chaunce, [1798]; 92707 (Drawer case 38 drawer 6, Item 87)
- Mathematical calculations for a pump, 92706 (Box McComb box 1, Item 007 verso)
- McComb Property alteration ink, MR: "Plan for improving the property of Jno. McComb corner of Broadway & Amity Lane", 92705 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 215)
- McComb Property alteration ink, LL-LR: "Sketch showing how the Lots on corner of Broad way and Amity Lane can be improved by being divided into Six Lots", 1827; May; 92704 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 216)
- McComb, plan of lots, truss of [Bleecker St. Church], 1825; 92703 (Box McComb Box 11, Item 190b verso)
- McComb's Lots, Caroline Street ink, LC: "Plan for improving Jn.o McComb's Lot-", 92702 (Box McComb Box 17, Item 343)
- McComb's Projects, attrib. "Buildings designed by Jn.o McComb with the exception of the Steeple of St. Johns Church": ink, LL-LR, with border, 92701 (Box McComb Box 22, Item 338)
- Mechanical, boat Pencil, LL-LC: "Plan & Section of a Boat for Carring Stone H.", [1794]; 92700 (Box McComb box 4, Item 79)
- Mechanical, unidentified, 92699 (Box McComb box 2, Item 35)
- Monuments, 3, Church, unidentified, 92698 (Box McComb box 4, Item 067b)
- Moore, Rev. Benjamin house ink, LL-LC: "Basement Story", 1794; or [1802]; 92697 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 406)
- Moore, Rev. Benjamin house ink, LL-LR: "Plan of a House design'd for Rev-d Benjamin Moore at Greenwich-", 1794(?);orighouse 1802c.; 92696 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 405)
- Mouldings and decorative details Foliage designs between circles, 92695 (Box McComb Box 17, Item 330)
- Murray St. Church ink, MR: "Capital & Base for Gallery Column full Size", 1811; 92694 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 144)
- Murray St. Church Ink, LL-LR: "Ground Plan of Murray Street Church", 1811; 92693 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 133)
- Murray St. Church ink, MR: "Mouldings for the church in Murray Street-", 1811; 92692 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 145)
- Murray St. Church S.s., graphite, LL-LR: [Murray St. Presbyterian or St. John's Chapel?], 1811; 92691 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 137)
- Murray St. Church S.s., graphite, LL-LC: [St. John's Chapel or Murray St. Presbyterian?], 1811; 92690 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 138)
- Murray St. Church, 1811; 92689 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 134)
- Murray St. Church, 1811; 92688 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 139)
- Murray St. Church graphite, LC: "Murray Street Church", 1811; 92687 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 135)
- Murray St. Church, 1811; 92686 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 136)
- Murray St. Church Ink, LL-LC: "Half Cap for Ionic Pilasters for Murray St. Church", 1811; 92685 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 140)
- Murray St. Church, attrib. Molding profile: attrib., 92684 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 321)
- New York Battery Ink, MR: "Plan Elevations & Sections a Furnace for Heating Ba[llshot] as Executed on the N. York Battery By John MComb", 92683 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 91)
- New York Hospital "A Front view of the New York Hospital, -": LL-LR, 1776; 92682 (Box McComb Box 22)
- Nicomedes Instrument ink, UC-UR: "Nicomedes Instrument for diminishing columns", 92681 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 427)
- Nilo Statue pencil, LL-LR: "Nilo Statua di marmo bigio gia nel Cortile delle Statue in Vaticano", 92680 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 303)
- North Dutch Church ink, LL-LR: "Front Elevation of the North dutch Church by John McComb", 1769; 92679 (Box McComb Box 13, Item 220)
- North Dutch Church ink, ML-MR: "Plan & Side Elevation of North dutch Church by John Mc.Comb 1772, 1769", 92678 (Box McComb Box 13, Item 219)
- Old Presbyterian Church Ink, LC-LR: "Framing of the Roof of the Old Presbyterian Church", 92677 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 167 verso)
- Ornamental detail sketch [band of ornament, gothicized palmettes of later Eastlake designs], 92676 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 326)
- Painshill garden pump A Section of a New Engine in Painshill Garden for Supplying a Lake which work'd by one horse only in one hour raises to the height of 12 feet, 1771, Feb; 92675 (Box McComb box 1, Item 7)
- [Palladian villa] country house, unidentified, 93203 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 244)
- Panopticon Panopticon Plan for a Prison for Juvenile offenders. Ink UR, 92674 (Box McComb box 2, Item 26)
- Park Theatre, attributed ink, UC: "Plan of Theater", [1795-1798]; 92673 (Box McComb Box 13, Item 224)
- Pavilion Elevation, 92672 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 124)
- Perspective studies Three perspective studies; two landscapes, 1 geometric volumes, 92671 (Box McComb box 2, Item 33)
- Pilaster, study "Detailed study for cap & fluting of pilaster": attributed, 92670 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 392 verso)
- Pissoir ink, LR: "Design for a Pissoir", 92669 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 414)
- Plan (concentric), unidentified, 1818; 92668 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 319)
- Plan, unidentified, 92667 (Box McComb Box 17, Item 330 verso)
- Plan, unidentified, 92666 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 174 verso)
- Plan, unidentified, 92665 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 174 verso)
- Plans - rectangular, unidentified, 92664 (Box McComb Box 21, Item 452)
- Potters Field Lodge, attributed Ink, UC-UR: "Plan & Elevation of the Lodge at the arsenal the Potters Field August 16, 1808 Jas. Williams [field Engineer?]", 1808; August 16; 92663 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 148)
- Potters Field Powder House, attributed Ink, LC: "Plan of the Powder House at Potters Field", 92662 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 149)
- Princeton Theological Seminary ink, LC-LR: "Plan designed for the Theological Seminary at Princeton", 92661 (Box McComb box 6, Item 115)
- Public Building, unidentified, [1820]; 92660 (Box McComb Box 13, Item 227)
- Public Building, unidentified, 1820; June 6; 92659 (Box McComb Box 13, Item 226)
- Public Building, unidentified ink, LC: "Park - Fronts", 1820; June 10; 92658 (Box McComb Box 13, Item 228)
- Public building, unidentified [attrib] elevation, 92657 (Box McComb box 1, Item 16)
- Pulpit, [1802]; 92656 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 317)
- Pulpit, unidentified church, 92655 (Box McComb box 3, Item 059a recto)
- Real Estate Lot Map, 92654 (Box McComb Box 21, Item 437)
- Real Estate Map - Farm, 1812; Aug. 12; 92653 (Box McComb Box 21, Item 439)
- Reservoir Ink, LC: "Elevation of the Reservoir", July 23, 1800 ink, LL; 92652 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 94)
- Reservoir, 1794, c.; 92651 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 89)
- Reservoir Ink, ML-MR: "Elevation of a Reservoir of 100.000 Gallons-", 92650 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 95)
- Reservoir to contain one million gallons Ink, UL-UR: "Three Sections of different designs for a Reservoir to contain One Million of Gallons", 92649 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 88)
- [Residences - conceptual], 93202 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 257)
- Residence - 2 family, unidentified Town house: attributed, 92648 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 250)
- Residence - circular, unidentified ink, LC: "30' Diam.r", 92647 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 254)
- Residence - Queen St., unidentified ink, LC: "Queen Street", 92646 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 249a recto)
- Residence semi-detached, unidentified, 92645 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 248)
- Residence semi-detached, unidentified, 92644 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 247)
- Residence, unidentified, 92643 (Box McComb box 1, Item 017b)
- Residence, unidentified, 92642 (Box McComb box 6, Item 105)
- Residence, unidentified, 92641 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 96)
- Residence, unidentified, 92640 (Box McComb box 6, Item 106)
- Residence, unidentified ink, LR: "Elevation drawn by Mr John MComb Senr", 92639 (Box McComb Box 13, Item 221)
- Residence, unidentified, 92638 (Box McComb box 6, Item 110a recto)
- Residence, unidentified, 92637 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 256)
- Residence, unidentified, 92636 (Box McComb box 6, Item 108)
- Residence, unidentified, 92635 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 243)
- Residence, unidentified ink, LC: "Front", 92634 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 251)
- Residence, unidentified, 92633 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 242)
- Residence, unidentified, 92632 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 249b verso)
- Residence, unidentified [First floor plan], 92631 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 259)
- Residence, unidentified, 92630 (Box McComb box 6, Item 107)
- Residence, unidentified ink, MC: "Basement Story", 92629 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 253)
- Residence, unidentified pencil, LC: "50'. Front.", 92628 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 235)
- Residence, unidentified, 92627 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 245)
- Residence, unidentified, 92626 (Box McComb box 6, Item 110b verso)
- Residence, unidentified, 92625 (Box McComb box 6, Item 109)
- Residence, unidentified, 92624 (Box McComb box 1, Item 12)
- Residence, unidentified, 92623 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 260 recto)